Hello hi friends welcome to our channel
friends as time changes, so does the
need and expenses of health insurance.
Keeping this in mind, ICICI Lombard has
launched a new health insurance plan
called Help Peel and Health Slide.
In this video, we are going to discuss
these plans in detail and compare them
with the previous plans so that you can
decide for yourself which plan you
want to take. Friends, before moving ahead,
I would like to tell you that neither I
am an agent nor I get commission from any company.
My purpose of making this video is that you should
understand the details of the plan yourself and use the best plan for yourself
which fulfils all your needs.
Friends, I would request you to
definitely subscribe to our channel friends
and ring the bell that you
see on the screen.
Friends, before going into the details of the plan,
I would like to tell you something about ICICI Lombard. According to the
IRDA 2019 report,
Maximum Health in 2019
Insurance policies have been
started by ICICI Lombard and this number is more than 42%.
In such a case, there is a long tyre of
Z Plus for cashless treatment from hospital.
So let us now move ahead and understand the
details of the policy. Friends, this policy
is available in total four variants, first is
Help Shield and second is Health LED. If you are looking for a policy of Rs 5 to
10 lakh, then
both these policies are for you. If you
want to take Rs 5250 Lucky policy, then this policy gets
converted into Help Shield Plus and
Help The Helpless. So we will
discuss in detail the features and changes made in all these new plans. Let us
move ahead
and take the first feature in
hospitalization charges. Here your
hospitalization should be
less than half an hour and
all your medical expenses like doctor
consultation fees, recharges, su-vichar, juice,
blood oxygen, Shyam Discovered are covered. Next, let us talk about
hospitalization, that is, whatever
medical expenses are there before hospitalization, there is a
limit in all these four.
Similarly, there
is a limit for TDS in post hospitalization.  Friends, let's now talk about
width. There have been a lot of changes here.
Subscribe to the unlimited sum assured
benefit. That is, if you go to MS Word, you can
withdraw it on Wednesday unlimited time. If
you compare it with before, then there
too, it could be availed only in one policy. But the
thing to note is that this sum assured benefit
cannot be availed for the same person.
Friends, let's talk about additional sum
insured. If you do not fly any airplane, then
when you go to renew the policy,
an additional ten percent sum
insured is set for you. But whenever
you click, it is reduced back to the same rate.
To protect this, a new feature has been added called
Additional Sum Insured. If your total
annual plan is very less than Rs. 5000, then your
ten percent addition will become
total. For any policy, it
can increase up to 50% by being combined.  For example, if
you have a policy of Rs 10 lakh and in the first year
your insurance was 2016, then ten percent will be added to this policy
and this policy will become
11.00 lakhs. Similarly, next
year also you claim for Schezwan,
romantic lead ten percent i.e. the
policy will become Barla. In the same way, it can be
increased by maximum 50% i.e. up to 15 lakhs. Let's
talk about front neck, see,
in the new policy of treatment, everything is covered and there is no
restriction. In day care, those
treatments are covered where your
hospitalization is less than 10 years,
such as cataract chemotherapy etc.
Friends, the next unique feature is World
Wide In Coverage which has been introduced,
Help Sheet Plus and Health Tips, that is,
if you take 15x more insurance and you
can get treatment anywhere worldwide,
but you will have to pay ten percent of the claim amount.
Friends, and one new feature which has been
added is Air Ambulance, if for
any reason you need immediate air  If you have to transport through an ambulance, then all the
expenses up to the sum insured will be covered.
And
if we talk about normal road transportation, then there
is coverage up to hospitalization at ₹15. Friends, similarly, there
is another feature called Claim Protector, which is a new
feature. It is available in the Free Leg Plus
policy. Friends, even if you are
hospitalized,
consumables like creams,
bandages, heart phlox, Gautam, etc. are deleted at the time of reimbursement.
But this new feature of ICC is
non-subscriber. Similarly, another feature
which is available in the above policy,
like due to the progress of time and by
adding this, the appointed committee will keep increasing every year
and it depends on the inflation rate i.e.
Consumer Price Index Government.
Apart from these features, ICICI is also
introducing some more features which are
available only in Health LED Plus.
So let us look at all these features one by one.
First of all, there is Maternity Plus OPD
benefit.  In maternity, you get child care, be it
normal delivery, cesarean
or medical termination,
but here the limit has been fixed
for normal delivery, it is 50 and the
most important thing is that here the waiting
period is of three years. If we talk about OPD benefit, then
maximum you get
10 patient treatment benefits in one policy.
If your hospitalization is
more than 10 days, then you will
get a telecopy and if it is more than 10 days, then
you will get a certificate of value which is Rs 10,000.
Another exclusive feature of
Nursing Home Plus is Nursing Home Plus. The company has tweeted post
hospitalization, if there is any experience at the nursing home, then
it is
covered up to that maximum. This is the maximum subscription. If we
talk about comparison benefits, then if your
hospitalization is more than 5 days, then
subscribe. If any of your services are free, then
you will
get the next service patient increase without any additional
cost. Your total time shot increases in this way to
two times the original amount.  It is possible
and these benefits are in addition to the additional time shot, that is, you will
get that and
this super no claim bonus will also be added.
Friends, here I would like to tell you that
ICICI has introduced many new features,
but for these additional features you have to pay a
very high premium in the Health Elite class.
We will see the
premium of all these features later.
Before going into that, let us look at some such features which are
quite common and the rest are covered in the company's policy.
If you are getting an organ transplant
and if we
talk about the entries related to hospitalization of the donor, then that is also a burden.
In this policy, subscribe to
Ayurveda, Yoga, Unani etc. but here
your treatment should be done in a government
registered medical hospital only. The
next feature is domiciliary
treatment. If for some reason you are
not able to go to the hospital for hospitalization
or beds are not available in the hospital,
hence nowadays due to shortage of chairs, then you
can get treatment at home, but the
condition here is that your treatment should be for more than three days
and should be done by a doctor or
medical practitioner.  It should be under supervision,
this is a very useful feature
because of today's videos, especially in ICICI
policies, there is a balance program in which
if you enroll in activities like gym, then
you get some points
which can be used for polygraph test. It is
very important to have this before taking any policy,
so the first exception is the waiting period,
whenever you take a policy, then you
cannot make any claim in the first three days,
except accident, next waiting
period is for free existing, which is
two years, that is, your existing ones
like cataract, joint
replacement stones etc. will be
withdrawn after two years of taking the policy or
due to this, their medical treatment
was also not covered in this policy, they did
not subscribe, all these scores will be available in the policies of other companies as
well, let's move ahead
and compare it with the old one,
if Ram takes premium for himself
and his insurance is for thirty years,
if he takes a help sheel, then his
annual premium will be Rs.
Eleventh is 1000 1000. If
we compare it with iHealth, which is the
old health insurance plan from ICC, then the
premium there is 0. So as you
can see, the new plan has
more features, but for that you will have to pay an additional
premium. Also, the premium for Ghrit is
quite high because
you are getting many unique features there. Similarly,
if Ram had taken a policy for himself at 0, then the
subscription would have been 30, appointed at 130, 210, which is
quite high. And for iHealth, which is an old
question, the premium there would have been 1007.
Friends, if you take a policy for 2 years at the same
premium, then
you will also get some traditional discounts.
Looking at these prelims, my
suggestion would be that you use HelpSheel Plan.
If you want to understand the line up to 10 lakhs
and if you want to increase it above 15 lakhs, then
choose HelpSheel Plus because
Harold Daily Plus definitely has features,
but its premium has to be quite
high. And here I would
like to say that  That there is one of these plans
and this is the guidelines of IRDA,
here CR is related to another feature,
if you buy on Amazon then there will be no additional sum
insured and if you go to
renew the policy then you will get a bonus.
Hello friends Ramesh, even if you
clean the policy with this, this benefit
is applicable till March 31, 2021.
Friends, I hope you liked this video.
Friends, I have also reviewed health insurance plans of
other companies like SDLC Max Bupa
Star Health Insurance in my channel.
You
must watch those videos as well so that you can
take the best decision for yourself.
Friends, do not forget to subscribe to our channel
and enjoy the time you see on the screen so
that you
get my latest videos first. Do like this video as
well and
share it with your friends and family. Thank you
and stay